A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Trustees Bulletins FA1126
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Trustees Bulletins
1937-1962
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA1126
3.8 Cubic Feet 24 volumes, 10 standard document boxes.
Arrangement
Chronological
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Each bulletin often contains 4 or 5 articles spanning a wide range of Foundation funded projects.
Biographical / Historical
The Confidential Monthly Report for the Information of the Trustees was first published in 1937 and was issued for the final time in January 1962, by then titled The Confidential Report for the Information of the Trustees (commonly known as the Trustees Bulletins). The editor for most of the period of publication was George Gray, a freelance science journalist hired by Rockefeller Foundation president Raymond Fosdick to begin writing and editing the monthly reports. Mr. Gray published his final issue in May 1957. William C. Cobb became the editor beginning with the December 1957 issue. The Confidential Report of January 1960 includes an obituary for Mr. Gray, which offers some history of the publication he edited for twenty years.
- Trustees Bulletins, 1937-1939 (Box 1)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1940-1942 (Box 2)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1943-1945 (Box 3)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1946-1948 (Box 4)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1955-1956 (Box 8)
- Trustees Bulletins, 1957-1958 (Box 9)
- Trustees Bulletins and Index, 1959-1962 (Box 10)